<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dan Han on Dan Han</title>
    <link>https://dhan1024.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dan Han on Dan Han</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Hospital Financial Outcomes under the 340B Drug Pricing Program – A Tale of Two Payment Systems</title>
      <link>https://dhan1024.github.io/project/working-340b-hospital-financial-outcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dhan1024.github.io/project/working-340b-hospital-financial-outcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 340B Drug Pricing Program entitles about 45% of U.S. hospitals to steep discounts on most outpatient drugs.  Due to a predominant mix of public payers that reimburse at costs, the financial implications of 340B for Critical Access Hospitals (CAH) differ widely from those for their non-CAH peers but have received little attention in the literature or policy world.  In this work, I present the stark contrast of 340B&amp;rsquo;s financial impact between CAHs and non-CAH hospitals. Using event studies that exploit the timing of hospitals joining 340B and hospital-level data, I document an increase in profit margin and supply of outpatient drugs at non-CAH hospitals, but little change to either margin or supply at CAHs under 340B, which corroborates findings from previous research based on patient-level data. Accompanying these changes in supply and margin, or the lack thereof, profits go up for non-CAH hospitals but decrease for CAHs. To explain why most CAHs participate in 340B despite the foregone revenue, I show that rising drug costs along with declining cash appear to motivate a high take-up rate. I also find that 340B benefits CAHs primarily by freeing up cash for meeting other operating expenses - a result robust to excluding hospitals that discontinued unprofitable services during the study period. While the negative effect on profits for CAHs spill over to a reduction in the offering of unprofitable services, the extra surplus obtained by non-CAH hospitals under 340B does not translate into an increase in the offering of unprofitable services. As a complementary approach, I estimate similar effects for non-CAH hospitals using a fuzzy regression discontinuity design that exploits an eligibility threshold specific to these hospitals, which bolsters my main results. These findings provide direct evidence that some non-CAH hospitals are capitalizing on 340B, and raise concerns over the program’s unanticipated effect on CAHs’ financial stability.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of the 340B Drug Pricing Program on Critical Access Hospitals: Evidence from Medicare Part B</title>
      <link>https://dhan1024.github.io/project/jmp-340b-critical-access-hospitals-part-b-drug/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dhan1024.github.io/project/jmp-340b-critical-access-hospitals-part-b-drug/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 340B Drug Pricing Program allows qualifying public and not-for-profit hospitals to acquire most outpatient drugs from manufacturers with discounts ranging from 20 to 50 percent of the cost of the drugs. Since the Affordable Care Act (ACA) extended hospital eligibility for 340B, over 1,000 Critical Access Hospitals (CAHs) have joined the program. Because CAHs are reimbursed by Medicare at 101% of costs, they receive less payment per Part B-covered outpatient drug under the 340B program. This creates a unique circumstance in which the behavioral response of CAHs and the implications to their patients remain not well understood. Leveraging the 340B expansion and the geographic variation in the outpatient market share of CAHs, I show in a difference-in-difference (DiD) framework that allowing CAHs to participate in 340B led to a significant reduction in total payment and beneficiary cost sharing for Part B drugs per patient with little change to Part B drug utilization. Since Part B coinsurance for services provided by CAHs is based on charges (list prices) instead of total payment, I find that the observed reduction in beneficiary cost sharing under 340B was driven by CAHs lowering outpatient drug charges upon becoming eligible for 340B (DiD) or participating in 340B (event study). I argue that the pass-through of 340B discounts to patients was not financially motivated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
