<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dan Han on Dan Han</title>
    <link>https://dhan1024.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dan Han on Dan Han</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Hospital Financial Outcomes under the 340B Drug Pricing Program – A Tale of Two Payment Systems (Working Paper)</title>
      <link>https://dhan1024.github.io/project/working-340b-hospital-financial-outcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dhan1024.github.io/project/working-340b-hospital-financial-outcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 340B Drug Pricing Program entitles about 45% of U.S. hospitals to steep discounts on most outpatient drugs.  Due to a predominant mix of public payers that reimburse at costs, the financial implications of 340B for Critical Access Hospitals (CAH) differ widely from those for their non-CAH peers but have received little attention in the literature or policy world.  In this work, I present the stark contrast of 340B&amp;rsquo;s financial impact between CAHs and non-CAH hospitals. Using event studies that exploit the timing of hospitals joining 340B and hospital-level data, I document an increase in profit margin and supply of outpatient drugs at non-CAH hospitals, but little change to either margin or supply at CAHs under 340B, which corroborates findings from previous research based on patient-level data. Accompanying these changes in supply and margin, or the lack thereof, profits go up for non-CAH hospitals but decrease for CAHs. To explain why most CAHs participate in 340B despite the foregone revenue, I show that rising drug costs along with declining cash appear to motivate a high take-up rate. I also find that 340B benefits CAHs primarily by freeing up cash for meeting other operating expenses - a result robust to excluding hospitals that discontinued unprofitable services during the study period. While the negative effect on profits for CAHs spill over to a reduction in the offering of unprofitable services, the extra surplus obtained by non-CAH hospitals under 340B does not translate into an increase in the offering of unprofitable services. As a complementary approach, I estimate similar effects for non-CAH hospitals using a fuzzy regression discontinuity design that exploits an eligibility threshold specific to these hospitals, which bolsters my main results. These findings provide direct evidence that some non-CAH hospitals are capitalizing on 340B, and raise concerns over the program’s unanticipated effect on CAHs’ financial stability.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of the 340B Drug Pricing Program on Outpatient Drug Utilitzation and Spending at Critical Access Hospitals (Job Market Paper)</title>
      <link>https://dhan1024.github.io/project/jmp-340b-critical-access-hospitals-part-b-drug/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dhan1024.github.io/project/jmp-340b-critical-access-hospitals-part-b-drug/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 340B Drug Pricing Program allows qualifying public and not-for-profit providers to acquire most outpatient drugs from manufacturers at discounted prices. Since the Affordable Care Act (ACA) extended 340B eligibility, over 1,000 Critical Access Hospitals (CAHs) have joined the program. Because CAHs are reimbursed by Medicare at 101% of costs, they receive less payment per Medicare Part B drug under 340B, which leads to unique incentives of which the impact and implication are not well understood. In this study, I examine the effects of 340B on Medicare Part B drug utilization and spending among patients treated in CAHs through the ACA&amp;rsquo;s 340B expansion. Using difference-in-difference methods, I find that the 340B expansion led to a significant decline in total payment and beneficiary cost sharing for Part B drugs per patient without any obvious effect on Part B drug utilization. Since Part B coinsurance at CAHs is based on charges (list prices) instead of total payment, I show that the observed negative effect of 340B on beneficiary cost sharing has been driven by CAHs reducing the average unit charge for outpatient drugs. I also argue that CAHs were not motivated financially to pass along 340B discounts to patients.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
