<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Dan Han</title>
    <link>https://dhan1024.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Dan Han</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dhan1024.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hospital Financial Outcomes under the 340B Drug Pricing Program – A Tale of Two Payment Systems</title>
      <link>https://dhan1024.github.io/project/working-340b-hospital-financial-outcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dhan1024.github.io/project/working-340b-hospital-financial-outcome/</guid>
      <description>The 340B Drug Pricing Program entitles about 45% of U.S. hospitals to steep discounts on most outpatient drugs. Due to a predominant mix of public payers that reimburse at costs, the financial implications of 340B for Critical Access Hospitals (CAH) differ widely from those for their non-CAH peers but have received little attention in the literature or policy world. In this work, I present the stark contrast of 340B&amp;rsquo;s financial impact between CAHs and non-CAH hospitals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of the 340B Drug Pricing Program on Critical Access Hospitals: Evidence from Medicare Part B</title>
      <link>https://dhan1024.github.io/project/jmp-340b-critical-access-hospitals-part-b-drug/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dhan1024.github.io/project/jmp-340b-critical-access-hospitals-part-b-drug/</guid>
      <description>The 340B Drug Pricing Program allows qualifying public and not-for-profit hospitals to acquire most outpatient drugs from manufacturers with discounts ranging from 20 to 50 percent of the cost of the drugs. Since the Affordable Care Act (ACA) extended hospital eligibility for 340B, over 1,000 Critical Access Hospitals (CAHs) have joined the program. Because CAHs are reimbursed by Medicare at 101% of costs, they receive less payment per Part B-covered outpatient drug under the 340B program.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>